we'll just do about 10 minutes and we'll
do another meditation in the second hour
today uh
but I
at least once this week
I would like to take you through how to
start a meditation and I know you did it
a hundred times
but I want to make sure everyone's doing
it okay
so just once this week we'll do a proper
preparation for meditation a mental
preparation okay and uh
I've been doing this for almost 50 years
and it's I still enjoyed doing I it's
very beautiful and and I I don't
meditate without doing this
uh so I'll do it every day when I
meditate I do this every day
and um
I think it's I think it's a beautiful
way to it's beautiful to do it once a
day
okay so uh I I spend
a lot of time to get ready for a
meditation mentally
and it takes about I don't know
10 15 minutes just to go into a
meditation okay so I strongly advise you
to do it
and get used to it and you don't have to
do it every day if you're on a short
schedule if you're the treasurer of some
major city in Colorado
you can
shorten it or go straight to your
meditation or but uh
maybe a couple times a week
do a nice preparation
[Music]
after almost 50 years of meditating I or
actually it is more than 50 years
um
I still think it's good to start uh with
a breathing practice
in
10 breaths just doesn't do it for me I
need a hundred breaths it's about five
minutes
so
we're gonna do a hundred breaths you're
gonna
lose count three or four times that's
okay come back
focus on the exhale first and then on
the inhale
foreign
then we'll go through the seven
steps to preparation and
the first step is supposed to be
prostration personally
I like to choose
someone
that I've been around in the last week
or so who is an inspiration to me and I
do a mental
prostration and oftentimes they are not
a Buddhist they are just
someone who is
is acting in a very
good way
and who inspires me and somebody I I
would like to be like them so I do a
mental prostration
by thinking of someone
who is inspiring to me and it's not
necessarily a famous person or something
oftentimes it's
just someone I meant
doing something beautiful for other
people
the next one is prostration
or offering
so I'd like to
imagine that I'm offering them something
and I I always come back personally to
offering them something good I did in
the last week or so
I make a small offering
of something
that I did good in the last few days
the third step here is uh
confession or
admitting some mistake I made in the
last week or so
so trying to think of some
mistake you've made
and
be honest about it it helps a lot to
purifier Karma to
sorry
admit a mistake that we made
in the last week or so
eventually it helps a lot to tell
somebody else
it's good to do it in your meditation
but it's nice to have some friends that
you can
share your mistakes with then you can
really improve quickly
and then share
something good you did with this person
in the last week
people have a natural tendency to
focus on their mistakes and we all
some trouble to admit when we're doing
something right
without Pride
so don't be
afraid to
admit that you're doing a lot of good
things
and just choose one
good thing and without Pride
Rejoice be happy
thank you
in the next step is to ask for teachings
number five
and
for me uh
teachings might come in two different
ways one is uh
oftentimes when I'm
looking at the great books
the Great
Buddhist books
I see I see beautiful teachings from my
day I see things that are going to help
me
today
and then oftentimes
I'll get teachings from other people
either somebody will say something sweet
and I'll get a teaching from it or
someone will challenge me
someone will cause me some trouble
and then I will
take a teaching from that so
ask ask for those teachings
and pray
that you get positive teachings and
teachings too difficult
difficult things and difficult people
and number six uh ask your teachers to
stay
I have a lot of teachers who come to me
in in the world or who are looking to me
through the Great
also have some very
my dearest teachers are still alive and
ask them to stay in your life
foreign
normally we would start our meditation
whatever is our
meditation that we're working on
and then after that we would dedicate
the good Karma I like to
think of a specific people I know who
are having a hard time
maybe they are sick or
or maybe
they're having a hard time personally
in their family life or something and
then I will
send the Good Karma of the meditation to
them
so let's dedicate the karma
and then slowly open your eyes
take a stretch
drink something if you're in Arizona you
have to drink
foreign
[Music]
goes through the brain the blood is
mostly water
if you don't drink you get stupid
seriously